&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：为了更具体地理解这一点，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: To understand this a little bit more concretely,
我想浏览一段代码，在几秒钟内浏览一下
I wanna walk through a piece of code which within a few seconds of glancing at
你可以在你的脑海中执行并说我知道这个程序要做什么。
you can in your mind have executed and said I know what this program is gonna do.
但事实证明，这个代码比我们复杂得多
But it turns out there's a lot more complexity to this code than we
通常用来处理。
are typically used to dealing with.
我会试着在接下来的几分钟里训练你思考这个代码
And I'm gonna try to train you over the next few minutes to think about this code
在某种程度上更接近JavaScript引擎思考它的方式。
in a way that more closely matches the way the JavaScript engine thinks about it.
所以我们要这样做，这听起来有点愚蠢
So we're gonna do that by way of what's gonna sound like a bit of a silly
锻炼。
exercise.
但希望它会足够轻松，让你继续参与和感兴趣。
But hopefully it'll be lighthearted enough to keep you engaged and interested.
我们要假装一场对话正在进行
We're going to pretend as if a conversation is happening
在这个JavaScript程序的处理中。
in this processing of the JavaScript program.
将会有两个演员，两个实体将会说话。
There's going to be two actors, two entities that are going to be talking.
一个是编译器，处理JavaScript程序的东西。
One is the compiler, the thing that's processing the JavaScript program.
另一个是作用域管理器，作用域管理器使
The other one is the scope manager, and scope manager is the one that makes
水桶，做弹珠，把弹珠放进去。
buckets, makes marbles, drops the marbles in.
是编译器说，嘿，我有这个东西，而且
It's the compiler who says, hey, I have this thing, and
是作用域经理说，我要制定一个计划
it's the scope manager who says, I'm gonna make a plan for
我要为水桶制定计划，为大理石制定计划。
that, I'm gonna make a plan for a bucket and make a plan for a marble.
这将是我们通过程序的第一步，就是编译步骤。
And that'll be our first pass through the program, is that compilation step.
在我们制定了所有的计划之后，
And then after we've set up all those plans,
然后我们会回来执行代码。
then we'll come back and execute the code.
因此，我们希望根据该对话来处理此代码。
So we want to process this code according to that conversation.
你可以跟着我，你真的可以大声说出来。
And you can follow along with me, you can literally speak out loud.
它对你有帮助，这是一种老师的把戏，
It helps you, it's sort of an old teacher trick,
如果我让你大声说出来，它就会更多地嵌入你的大脑。
if I get you to say this stuff out loud, it embeds it more in your brain.
所以我们一起走的时候我想让你大声跟我说话，
So as we go along I want you to speak out loud with me,
尽管听起来有点傻。
even though it sounds a little bit silly.
记住，在我们的处理阶段，在我们的编译阶段，
Remember, in our processing phase, in our compilation phase,
我们有一个作用域管理器和一个编译器。
we have a scope manager and we have a compiler.
所以我将扮演编译器与作用域管理器对话的角色。
So I'll play the part of compiler talking to a scope manager.
当我遇到，就像我在1号线上看到的，当我看到在线上，
And when I come across, as I see here on line 1, when I see on line,
var声明，无论是let还是const，或者
a var declaration, whether it's a let or a const, or
var目前并不相关。
a var isn't relevant at this moment.
但为了简单起见，我将使用vars。
But I'm gonna use vars just for the simplicity of illustration.
这是正式声明。
That's a formal declaration.
换句话说，我们在创造一个大理石。
In other words, we're creating a marble.
我们要知道用什么颜色做大理石，所以
And we gotta know what color to make that marble, so
我们必须有一些范围，我们要增加它。
we gotta have some scope that we're adding it to.
在这种情况下，显然是全局范围，好吗？
And in this case, obviously it's the global scope, okay?
为了我们讨论的简单性，
And just for the simplicity of our discussion,
我要用三原色。
I'm gonna use the three primary colors.
我要说外部全局作用域将是红色的桶和
I'm gonna say the outer global scope is gonna be the red bucket and
然后，只要我们有内桶，我们就会有蓝色和绿色，好吗？
then wherever we have inner buckets we'll have blue and green, okay?
所以我们有一个代表这个全局范围的红色桶，我，
So we have a red bucket that represents this global scope and I,
作为编译器，每当我看到像我在第1行上所做的正式声明时，
being the compiler, whenever I see a formal declaration like I do on line 1,
我要说，嘿，全球范围，嘿，红桶，我有一个正式的声明。
I'm gonna say, hey, global scope, hey, red bucket, I have a formal declaration.
我这里有一个大理石，你听说过这个叫老师的东西吗？
I have a marble here, have you ever heard of this thing called teacher?
我问这个问题是因为如果它已经知道一个标识符
And I'm asking this question because if it already knows about an identifier of
这个名字老师，它不需要做任何事情。
the name teacher, it doesn't need to do anything.
这是一个没有行动。
That's a no op.
没有重新声明这回事。
There's no such thing as redeclaration.
还好，太好了，你已经知道这个大理石了。
It's just okay, great, you already know about this marble.
但在这个特殊的情况下，因为这是编译器第一次
But in this particular case, since it's the first time that the compiler would
已经向全局范围询问了一个名为Teacher的变量，
have asked the global scope about a variable called teacher,
然后全球范围会说，不，从来没有听说过。
then the global scope's gonna say, nope, never heard of it.
但我现在为你创造了一个红色的大理石，
But I've created now a red marble for you and, pop,
现在我们刚刚把它扔进了红色的桶里。
now we just dropped it into the red bucket.
它实际上并没有被创造出来，直到它们真正被创造出来
It hadn't actually been created, that they don't get created for real until
执行，但从概念上讲，我们是根据我们在程序中看到的内容创建这个计划的。
execution, but conceptually we're creating this plan from what we see in the program.
所以，是的，全球范围内说，当然，我们会做一个红色的大理石
So yes, global scope says, sure, we'll make a red marble and
我们会把它扔进红色的桶里。
we'll drop it into the red bucket.
现在我们要做的就是寻找这些正式的声明。
Now what we're doing is looking for these formal declarations.
有时他们看起来就像1号线上的var老师。
And sometimes they look like on line 1 var teacher.
有时它们看起来像第3行、函数或其他类型的声明。
Sometimes they look like line 3, functions or another kind of declaration.
函数构成大理石，在这种情况下，
Functions make a marble, in this case,
第3行上的大理石将被称为other Class。
the marble on line 3 would be called otherClass.
这需要被添加到一些范围内。
And that needs to get added to some scope.
因此，如果我运行，作为编译器，第3行，一个正式的声明
So if I ran across, as the compiler, line 3, a formal declaration for
一个函数，我会与作用域管理器进行相同的对话。
a function, I would have the same conversation with the scope manager.
我想说，嘿，作用域管理器，编译器再次出现在这里。
I'd say hey, scope manager, compiler here again.
我找到了另一个正式声明，在本例中是名为other Class的大理石。
I found another formal declaration, in this case for a marble called otherClass.
你以前听说过这个标识符吗？
Have you ever heard of that identifier before?
在这种情况下，我的答案是什么？
And in this case, what's my answer gonna be?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：否。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：不，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Nope,
从来没听说过，但这里还有一个，什么颜色的大理石？
never heard of it, but here's another, what color marble?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：红色。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：红色大理石，因为我们还在全球范围内，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Red marble because we're still in the global scope,
这是另一个红色大理石，砰。
so here's another red marble, boop.
所以现在我们有两个红色的弹珠在红色的桶里。
So now we have two red marbles in the red bucket.
它负责标识符other Class
That takes care of the identifier otherClass
以及识别符教师。
as well as the identifier teacher.
现在，作为编译器，我足够聪明地意识到，这是一种特殊的
Now, I being the compiler am smart enough to realize, that's a special kind of
事情，因为函数产生作用域，所以它产生桶。
thing, because a function makes scopes, it makes buckets.
所以，嘿，示波器经理猜怎么着，我们还需要一个桶。
So, hey, scope manager guess what, we're gonna need another bucket.
为了延伸这个比喻，现在我们在里面创建一个桶
And to stretch this metaphor a little bit, now we're creating a bucket inside of
一个桶，就像一个巨大的桶，然后里面有一个很小的桶，好吗？
a bucket, so like a giant barrel and then a tiny little bucket inside, okay?
我知道这有点夸张了这个比喻。
I know it's stretching the metaphor a little bit.
但现在我们有了一个巨大的红色桶里面，嘿，
But now we had a giant red barrel and inside of it, hey,
作用域管理器我们需要一个蓝色的桶，因为它是一个函数。
scope manager we need a blue bucket, because it's a function.
所以作用域经理说，当然，现在我们有一个蓝色的桶，并且
So scope manager says, sure, now we got a blue bucket, and
现在我们讨论的是蓝色桶，让我们进入该函数并
now we are talking about the blue bucket, and let's step into that function and
将它作为自己的作用域来讨论，因为它的函数创建作用域。
talk about it as its own scope, since that's functions creates scopes.
那么我们的下一个正式声明在哪里？
So where's our next formal declaration then?
嗯，是在4号线，对吧？
Well, it's on line 4, right?
第4行有另一个正式声明，在本例中是一个名为teacher的变量。
Line 4 has another formal declaration, in this case for a variable called teacher.
所以，谈话将一如既往地继续，
So, the conversation is gonna continue exactly like before,
即使是同样的名字，同样的对话，我们也会说，嘿，
even though it's the same name, same conversation, we're gonna say, hey,
蓝桶，嘿，另一个类的作用域管理器。
blue bucket, hey scope manager for this other class.
我有一个叫老师的大理石的正式声明，听说过吗？
I have a formal declaration for a marble called teacher, ever heard of it?
现在这个问题的答案可能会让你感到惊讶，因为你可能会想，
Now the answer to that question might surprise you because you might think,
当然，我们在1号线上听说了！
sure, we heard about it on line 1!
但请记住，我们现在所说的是一个完全不同的桶。
But remember we're talking to an entire different bucket now.
我们说的是蓝色桶，不是红色桶，好吗？
We're talking to the blue bucket, not the red barrel, okay?
我知道这把比喻延伸得太薄了，好吧。
I know this stretches the metaphor horribly thin, okay.
但我们在和蓝色桶说话。
But we're talking to the blue bucket.
所以我们在说，嘿，蓝桶，你有没有一个叫老师的大理石？
So we're saying hey, blue bucket, do you have a marble called teacher?
蓝桶的反应是什么？
And what's blue bucket's response?
作用域经理会怎么说？
What's the scope manager going to say?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
凯尔·辛普森：但这是你的，什么颜色的大理石？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: But here's your, what color marble?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：蓝色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Blue marble.
凯尔·辛普森：这是你的蓝色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your blue marble.
好的，现在有两个弹珠放在两个不同颜色的桶里，
Okay, so now there are two marbles in two separate buckets of two different colors,
即使他们有相同的名字。
even though they have the same name.
跟我来？
Follow me?
顺便说一下，在相同名称的不同作用域中有两个变量，
By the way, having two variables at different scopes of the same name,
它有一个术语，叫做“影子”(Shadowing)。
that has a term, it's called shadowing.
听起来像是邪恶的东西，没什么不好的，
Sounds like sort of like evil or whatever, there's nothing bad about it,
跟踪完全没问题。
shadowing is entirely okay.
但也有影子的分支，
But there is an offshoot of shadowing,
也就是说，现在我们已经创建了一个称为教师的变量，
which is, now that we've created a variable called teacher,
我们在另一个班级范围内创建了一个称为教师的蓝色大理石。
we've created a blue marble called teacher in that other class scope.
好的，现在我们没有可能在词汇上引用
Well, now there's no possible way that we can reference lexically
行1中的变量。
the variable from line 1.
我们不能引用红色大理石，因为现在有了同样的蓝色大理石
We can't reference the red marble because now there's a blue marble of the same
名字，因为阴影。
name, because of the shadowing.
它完全可以，但它确实限制了我们可以访问的内容。
It's totally okay, but it does limit us from what we can access.
因为这些名字，它会匹配最近的名字，
Because those names, it would match the nearest one,
在这种情况下应该是蓝色大理石。
which in this case would be the blue marble.
跟我来？
Follow me?
因此，我们寻找任何其他正式声明。
So, we look for any other formal declarations.
我们在other Class函数中还能找到更多吗？
Do we find any more in the otherClass function?
我们看到了对console.log的引用，但没有看到更正式的声明。
We see a reference to console.log, but we see no more formal declarations.
所以我们完成了other Class函数。
So we're finished with the otherClass function.
现在我们退到什么颜色范围？
Now we step back out to what color scope?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：红色。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Red.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：红色范围，全局范围。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The red scope, the global scope.
我们寻找下一个正式的装饰。
And we look for the next formal decoration.
我们在哪条线上找到下一个正式装饰？
What line do we find the next formal decoration on?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：8。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：第8行怎么样？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: 8. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: How about line 8?
您可以在这里看到名为ask的标识符的正式函数声明。
You see here the formal function declaration for an identifier called ask.
谈话一如既往地继续。
The conversation continues exactly like before.
对话说，嘿，什么范围？
The conversation says, hey, what scope?
嘿？
Hey?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：全局。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：全球范围，嘿，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Global. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Global scope, hey,
红桶，我有一份正式的声明
red bucket, I have a formal declaration for
一个叫做Ask的标识符，听说过吗？
an identifier called ask, ever heard of it?
答案是？
And the answer is?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：否。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：没有，从来没有听说过。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Nope, never heard of it.
但这是你的？
But here's your?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red marble.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：红色大理石，太棒了，你完全遵循了。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Red marble, great, you're following perfectly.
有一个红色的大理石，因为我们在全球范围内。
There's a red marble, because we are in the global scope.
这就是大理石和红色桶相配的颜色。
And that's what color marble matches with the red bucket.
怎么了？
Yes?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：为什么我们跳过控制台日志？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Why did we skip over console log?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们没有从编译的角度跳过它。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We didn't skip over it from the perspective of compilation.
这是个好问题。
That is a good question.
编译器肯定会处理第5行并进行大量编译。
The compiler would have certainly handled line 5 and done a bunch of compilation.
它对我们的范围没有任何影响。
It doesn't have any impact on our scopes.
因此，我们将编译器理论的重点缩小到准备标识符和
So we've narrowed our focus of compiler theory to preparing our identifiers and
我们的范围。
our scopes.
做我们的大理石桶分类的事情。
Doing our marble bucket sorting thing.
所以我们只是跳过了无趣的细节
So we're just skipping over the uninteresting details at
这一点，对。
this point, right.
有一整门关于编译理论的课程
There's whole courses on compiler theory that would get into all
第5行的实质内容，但由于它不会创建或
the nitty gritty of line 5, but since it doesn't create or
访问我们范围内的任何变量，我们不需要担心它。
access any variables within our scopes, we don't need to worry about it.
说得通吗？
Make sense?
好的，问得好。
Okay, good question.
好的，我们刚刚做了一个红色的大理石叫Ask。
All right, so we just made a red marble called ask.
作为一个好的编译器，我们注意到它附加到一个函数上。
And being a good compiler we notice that's attached to a function.
你猜怎么着，作用域经理，我们还需要一个桶。
Guess what, scope manager, we're gonna need another bucket.
这个我们称之为绿色水桶。
This one we'll call the green bucket.
所以范围经理，你能为我们做一个绿色的水桶吗？
So scope manager, could you go ahead and make a green bucket for us.
作用域经理说肯定，现在我们进入绿色桶的作用域，
Scope manager says sure, and now we step into the scope of the green bucket,
标记为Ask的函数在这里，好的。
the function labeled ask here, okay.
因此，我们在该函数中寻找正式声明。
So we look for formal declarations in that function.
我们在哪里可以找到下一个正式声明？
Where do we find the next formal declaration?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：线路9。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Line 9.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：第9行，您可以看到在第9行，我有一个var声明，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Line 9, you see there on line 9 I have a var declaration,
所以这是真正的重复，谈话的方式完全相同。
so that's getting real repetitive, the conversation goes exactly the same way.
嘿绿色桶，嘿问的范围，我有一个正式的声明
Hey green bucket, hey scope of ask, I have a formal declaration for
一个叫做的识别符？
an identifier called?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Question.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：问题。&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：问题，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Question. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Question,
听说过他吗？
ever heard of him?
答案是？
And the answer is?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：不。凯尔·辛普森：但是？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Nope. &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: But?
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：这是你的绿色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Here's your green marble.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这是你的绿色大理石，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your green marble, right?
所以我们得到了一个绿色的大理石，砰的一声，我们把它扔到了绿色的桶里。
So we get a green marble and boop we drop it in the green bucket.
现在，这很关键，
Now, this is critical,
因为您会注意到第10行我们有一个对标识符的引用。
because you'll notice on line 10 we have a reference to an identifier.
这不是创造弹珠，所以在这个处理步骤中，我们不会担心
This isn't creating marbles, so in this processing step we're not gonna worry so
关于创造它。
much about creating it.
但我们必须弄清楚这些大理石是从哪里来的，
But we are going to have to understand where that marble comes from,
当我们在下一步执行代码时，这是什么颜色的大理石。
what color marble that is, when we execute the code in the next step.
所以我们正确地对大理石进行分类是非常关键的
So it's critical that we do this marble sorting correctly
当我们第一次处理代码时。
as we process the code the first time.
我们已经完成了Ask函数，对吗？
So we're done with the ask function, right?
没有更正式的声明。
There's no more formal declarations.
然后我们回到全局范围。
And then we step back out to the global scope.
我们在全局范围内找到任何更正式的声明吗？
Do we find any more formal declarations in the global scope?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
凯尔·辛普森：好吗？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Okay?
所以竖起大拇指，我们现在已经完成了处理阶段，
So thumbs up, we are now done with that processing stage,
这段代码的编译器阶段。
with that compiler phase of this code.
我们剩下的是所有水桶和弹珠的计划。
And what we are left with is a plan for all the buckets and all the marbles.
我们已经考虑了所有存在的作用域和
We've accounted for all the scopes that exist and
其中所有标识符都适合所有这些。
where all the identifiers fit into all of those.
包括对它们的引用，比如在第10行，我们知道那是什么颜色的大理石。
Including references to them like on line 10, we know what color marble that is.
你和我一起吗？
You with me?
我们都知道。
We know all of that stuff.
我们已经把所有的计划都安排好了。
We've got all that plan all laid out.
然后作为执行计划的一部分进行移交
That is then handed over as part of the execution plan so
虚拟机JavaScript引擎可以运行此代码。
that the virtual machine, the JavaScript engine, can run this code.
大家都跟我一起吗？
Everybody with me?
现在重要的是要注意，当我们执行代码时，
Now it's important to note that when we execute the code,
没有更多的声明了。
there's no more declarations for anything.
所有的瓶子都没了，
All the vars are gone,
本质上，因为我们不再需要声明任何东西。
essentially, because we don't need to declare anything anymore.
我们已经知道那会有什么用了，
We already know what that's gonna do,
因为我们在编译时就算出来了。
because we figured that stuff out at compile time.
所以，一个关键的外卖，不要错过这个。
So, one key takeaway, don't miss this.
一个关键的要点是，在词法范围内的语言中，JavaScript就是全部
One key takeaway is that in a lexically scoped language which JavaScript is all
我们正在处理的作用域，所有的词法作用域和
of the scopes that we're dealing with, all of the lexical scopes and
标识符，这都是在编译时确定的。
identifiers, that's all determined at compile time.
它不是在运行时确定的。
It's not determined at run time.
它在运行时使用，但在编译时确定。
It is used at run time, but it is determined at compile time.
而这一点之所以重要，是因为它允许引擎在很大程度上
And why that matters is, that allows the engine to much
更有效地优化，因为一切都是已知的，并且是固定的。
more efficiently optimize, because everything is known and it's fixed.
在运行时间期间没有任何东西可以确定这个大理石不再是红色的，
Nothing during the run time can determine that this marble is no longer red,
现在它是蓝色的。
now it's blue.
一旦我们处理完，我们已经知道它是什么颜色的大理石
Once we've processed through, we already know what color marble it is and
我们的讨论结束了。
we're done with that discussion.
这样，JavaScript引擎的工作效率就会更高。
So that allows the JavaScript engine to be much more efficient at its job.
你应该从中得到的启示是，
The takeaway that you should have from that is,
我所做的关于范围的决定是作者时间的决定。
the decisions that I've made about scope are author time decisions.
当我写这个函数，我把这个变量放在这里，
When I write this function and I put this variable here,
这意味着变量总是那个颜色的大理石。
it means that that variable is always gonna be that color marble.